Live for nothing, or die for something.
Rambo is a action, thriller, war film directed by Sylvester Stallone.
In Thailand, ex-Green Beret John James Rambo joins a group of mercenaries to venture into war-torn neighboring Myanmar
to rescue a group of Christian aid workers who have been kidnapped by a ruthless local infantry unit.
John Rambo, played by Sylvester Stallone.
Sarah, played by Julie Benz.
School Boy, played by Matthew Marsden.
Lewis, played by Graham McTavish.
Diaz, played by Reynaldo Gallegos.
En-Joo, played by Tim Kang.
Rambo is a 2008 American war action film co-written
and directed by Sylvester Stallone.
A sequel to Rambo III (1988), it is the fourth installment in the Rambo film
series based on the character created by author David Morrell.
Stallone stars as John Rambo, who leads a group of mercenaries into Burma to rescue
Christian missionaries, who have been kidnapped by a local infantry unit.
The film co-stars Julie Benz, Paul Schulze, Matthew Marsden, Graham McTavish, Rey
Gallegos, Tim Kang, Jake La Botz, Maung Maung Khin, and Ken Howard.
Rambo is dedicated to the memory of Richard Crenna, who had played
Colonel Sam Trautman in the previous films and died in 2003.
The rights to the Rambo franchise were sold to Miramax Films
in 1997 after Carolco Pictures went bankrupt.
Miramax intended to produce a fourth film but Stallone
was unmotivated to reprise the role.
The rights were then sold to Nu Image and Millennium Films in 2005, who
green-lit the film before the release of Rocky Balboa (2006).
Filming began in Thailand, Mexico, and the United
States in January 2007, and ended that May.
Rambo was theatrically released in the United States by Lionsgate Films and the
Weinstein Company on January 25, 2008, and in Germany by Warner Bros.
Pictures on February 14.
It received mixed reviews, with praise aimed at Stallone’s direction and performance, action sequences, and
musical score, but criticism for its plot, excessively graphic violence, and political commentary.
At the box office, it grossed $113.2 million worldwide against
a production budget between $47.5–50 million.
The film was followed by Rambo: Last Blood, released in 2019.
The film explores themes of snake, fight, missionary, boat, river.
The tone is intense.